<Actors>
	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_intro" description="Introduction" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Welcome! This tutorial will teach you the most crucial basics of Minetest.
				This tutorial assumes that you have not changed the default keybindings yet.

				Let's start for the most important keybindings right now:

					 Look around: Move the mouse
					 Walk forwards: [W]
					 Strafe left: [A]
					 Walk backwards: [S]
					 Strafe right: [D]
					 Action: [Right mouse button]
					Pause menu (you can exit the game here): [Esc]

				You will find signs with more introductionary texts throughout this tutorial.
				The "action" key has many uses. For now, let's just say you need it to read
				the signs. Look at one and right-click it to read it.

				To look at a sign, make sure you are close enough to it and the crosshair in the
				center of the screen points directly on the sign.

				You can exit the tutorial at any time, the world will be automatically saved.

				Now feel free to walk around a bit and read the other signs to learn more.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_minetest" description="Minetest" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Minetest itself is not a game, it is a game engine.
				To be able to actually play it, you need something called a "game".

				Don't worry, Minetest comes pre-installed with a rather simple default game,
				called "Minetest Game".

				This tutorial teaches you the basics of Minetest (the engine), things which are true for
				all games. This tutorial does not teach you how to play a particular game, not
				even the default one.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_cam" description="Player Camera" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[Minetest has 3 different views which determine the way you see the world.
				The three modes are:

				- First-person view (default)
				- Third-person view from behind
				- Third-person view from the front

				You can change the camera mode by pressing [C] (but you have to close this
				window first).

					 Switch camera mode: [C]]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_minimap" description="Minimap" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[Press the [V] key to make a minimap appear on the top right.
				The minimap helps you to find your way around the world.
				Press it again to toggle through different minimap modes and zoom levels.

				There are 2 minimap modes and 3 zoom levels.

				Surface mode is a top-down view of the world, roughly resembling the
				colors of the blocks this world is made on. It only shows the topmost
				blocks, everything below is hidden, like a satellite photo. Surface
				mode is useful if you got lost.

				Radar mode is more complicated. It displays the "denseness" of the area
				around you and changes with your height. Roughly, the more green an
				area is, the less "dense" it is. Black areas have many blocks. Use
				the radar to find caverns, hidden areas, walls and more. Currently,
				radar mode does not work in the tutorial. Sorry, you have to try it
				out in games.

				There are also two different direction modes. Normally, "up" on the minimap
				is always pointing to the North. But if you press [Shift]+[V], the minimap
				will instead rotate with your looking direction, so "up" is always your
				looking direction.

				In some games, the minimap may be disabled.

					 Toggle minimap mode: [V]
					 Toggle minimap rotating: [Shift]+[V]]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_runover" description="Small Abysses" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[This abyss behind this sign is so small that you can even walk over it,
				as long as you don't stop midway. But you can jump over it anyways, just to be,
				safe.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_jumpup" description="Jumping (1)" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[You can't reach this upper block by walking. But luckily, you are able to jump.
				For our purposes, you can jump just high enough to reach one block above you.
				But you can't two blocks high.
				Press the space bar once to jump at a constant height.

					 Jump: [Space]

				Now try it to continue.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_jumpover" description="Jumping (2)" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[Here is a slightly larger abyss. Luckily, you can also jump just far enough to
				cross a gap of this width. Don't worry, the abyss is not deep enough to hurt you
				when you fall down. There are stairs which lead back up here.

					 Jump: [Space]]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_sneak" description="Sneaking" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[Sneaking is a special move. As long as you sneak, you walk slower, but you are
				guaranteed to not accidentally fall off the edge of a block. This also allows you to
				"lean over" in a sense.
				To sneak, keep the sneak key pressed. As soon as you release the sneak key,
				you walk at normal speed again. Be careful not releasing the sneak key when you
				are at a ledge, you might fall!

					 Sneak: [Shift]

				Keep in mind that the [Shift] key is used for a large number of other things in Minetest.
				Sneaking only works when you are not in a liquid, stand on solid ground and are not at a
				ladder.

				You may try out sneaking at this little blocky pyramid.]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_orientation" description="Information about the following tutorial sections" 
			resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[From this point on, there will be branching paths. For orientation, we placed
				some arrow signs. They just show a short text when you hover them, that's all.

				You don't have to follow the sections in any particular order, with one exception,
				for which you will be informed.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_hotbar" description="Hotbar" 
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[At the bottom of the screen you see 8 squares. This is called the 'hotbar'.
				The hotbar allows you to quickly access some items from your inventory.
				In our case, the upper 8 slots in your inventory.
				You can change the selected item with the mouse wheel, if you have one, or with the
				number keys.

					 Select previous item in hotbar: [Mouse wheel up]
					 Select next item in hotbar: [Mouse wheel down]
					 Select item #N in hotbar: the key with the number #N

				The item you've selected is also the item you wield. This will be important later for
				tools, mining, building, etc.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_eat" description="Comestibles and Eating"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[In this chest you find some comestibles. Comestibles are items which instantly
				heal you when eaten. This removes the item from your inventory.
				To eat one, select the comestible in your hotbar, then click the left mouse button.
				Unlike other items, you cannot punch or attack while holding a comestible. To be able
				to attack, you have to select something else.
				Of course, this does not have to be the only way to heal you.

					 Eat comestible: [Left mouse button]

				Don't forget to take the gold ingot.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_chest" description="Chests"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Treasure chests are a common sight in Minetest. They are actually not built-in
				into the game.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_damageblock" description="Blocks Which Hurt You"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Careful! These spikes hurt you when you stand inside, so don't walk into them.
				Try to walk around and get the gold ingot.

				They damage you every second you stand in them.

				This is one of the many ways you can get hurt in Minetest.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_ladder" description="Climbing Ladders"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[This is a ladder. Ladders help you to climb up great heights or to climb down safely.
				To climb a ladder, go into the block occupied by the ladder and hold one of the
				following keys:

					 Climb up ladder: [Space]
					 Climb down ladder: [Shift]

				Note that sneaking and jumping do not work when you are at a ladder.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_swim" description="Swimming"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[What you see here is a small swimming pool. You are able to swim and dive.
				Diving usually costs you breath. While diving, 10 bubbles appear in the heads-up display.
				These bubbles disappear over time while diving and when you are out of bubbles,
				you slowly lose some health points. You have to back up to the surface from time to
				time to restore the bubbles.

				Movement in a liquid is slightly different than on solid ground:

					 Swim forwards: [W]
					 Swim backwards: [S]
					 Swim leftwards: [A]
					 Swim rightwards: [D]
					 Swim upwards: [Space]
					 Swim downwards: [Shift]

				At the bottom of the pool lies a gold ingot. Try to get it!]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_dive" description="Diving"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[To get to the other side, you have to dive here. Don't worry, the tunnel is not
				long. But don't stay too long in the water, or else you take damage.
				At the bottom of the pool lies a gold ingot. Try to get it!

					 Swim forwards: [W]
					 Swim backwards: [S]
					 Swim leftwards: [A]
					 Swim rightwards: [D]
					 Swim upwards: [Space]
					 Swim downwards: [Shift]]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_waterfall" description="Swimming up a Waterfall"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[You can easily swim up this waterfall. Go into the water and hold the space bar until you're
				at the top

					 Swim forwards: [W]
					 Swim backwards: [S]
					 Swim leftwards: [A]
					 Swim rightwards: [D]
					 Swim upwards: [Space]
					 Swim downwards: [Shift]]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_viscosity" description="Viscosity"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Minetest mods can introduce various liquids which differ in their properties.
				Probably the most important property is their viscosity. Here you have some
				pools which differ in their viscosity. Feel free to try them out.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_liquidtypes" description="Liquid sources and flowing liquids"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[Liquids behave somewhat weirdly in Minetest. Actually, there are 2 kinds of liquids.
				If you watched the waterfall closely, you may have noticed that there is a slight difference
				between the water blocks that make the waterfall, and those up here in the basin.

				Minetest distinguishes between liquid source and flowing liquid.

				A liquid source block is always a full cube.
				A flowing liquid block looks slightly different. Often, it is not a full cube, but has a more or less
				triangular shape. Also, flowing liquids usually have an unique "flowing" animation, but this may
				not be the case for all liquids.

				Up in the basin, you see four rows of liquid sources, followed by one row of flowing
				liquids, followed by the waterfall itself. The waterfall itself is solely made of flowing liquids.

				Liquid sources generate flowing liquids around them. Liquid sources can also exist on their own.
				Flowing liquids are not able to exist on their own. They have to originate from a liquid source.
				If the liquid source is gone, or the way to one is blocked, the flowing liquid will slowly dry
				out.

				To the right of this sign is a special block. When used, it will block the liquid flow.
				Use that block, being close enough and looking at it, and watch the waterfall dry out.

					 Use something: [Right mouse button]]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_pointing1" description="Pointing (1)"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[An important general concept in Minetest is pointing. As mentioned earlier,
				there is a crosshair in the center of the screen.

				You can point several things in Minetest:

				- Blocks
				- Dropped items
				- Other players
				- Many other things

				You can only point one thing at once, or nothing at all.
				When you're pointing a block, it is surrounded by a thin wireframe or it will
				be highlighted (you can change the style in your settings).
				When you're pointing an object, animal or another player, your crosshair will
				change its shape.

				To point something, three conditions have to be met:
				1. The thing in question must be pointable at all
				2. Your crosshair must be exactly over the thing in question
				3. You must be close enough to the thing

				When a thing is pointed, you can do different stuff with it; e.g. collecting it,
				punching it, building to it, etc. We come to all that later.

				Now collect that apple from the small tree in front of this sign, and the gold bar.
				To do that, you must point it and click with the left mouse button.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_pointing2" description="Pointing (2)"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[The distance you need to point to things solely depends on the tool you carry.
				Most tools share a default value but some tools may have a longer or shorter distance.

				At the moment, your only "tool" is the hand. It was good enough to collect the apple
				from the small tree.

				Above this sign hang some apples, but you cannot reach them by normal means. At the
				wall in front of this sign lies a special example tool which you can use to retrieve the apple
				from afar.

				To take the tool, point to it and click the left mouse button. Then select it with the
				mouse wheel or the number keys. You will learn more about tools in a different section.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_health" description="Health and Damage"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Unless you have damage disabled, all players start with 20 hit points (HP), represented
				by ten hearts in the heads-up display. One HP is represented by half a heart in this
				tutorial, but the actual representation can vary from game to game.

				You can take damage for the following reasons (including, but not limited to):
				- Falling too deep
				- Standing in a block which hurts you
				- Attacks from other players
				- Staying too long in a liquid

				In this tutorial, you can regain health by eating a comestible. This is only an example,
				mods and games may come with other mechanisms to heal you.

				When you lose all your hit points, you die. Death is normally not really that bad in Minetest.
				When you die, you will usually lose all your possessions. You are able to put yourself
				into the world immediately again. This is called "respawning". Normally you appear at a
				more or less random location.
				In the tutorial you can die, too, but don't worry about that. You will
				respawn at a special location you can't normally reach and keep all your posessions.
				Games may introduce special events on a player's death.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_death" description="Death and Respawning"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Oops! So it seems you just have died. Don't worry, you don't have lost any of your
				possessions and you have been revived. You are still in Tutorial World at a different
				location.

				You have arrived at the so-called respawn location of Tutorial World. You will
				always appear here after you died. This is called "respawning". In most worlds,
				however, you will respawn in a slightly randomized location.

				The tutorial uses a so-called fixed spawn point, so you respawn always at the same
				spot. This is unusual for singleplayer worlds, but in online play, some servers
				use fixed spawn points, too.

				Under normal conditions you would have lost all or a part of your possessions or some
				other bad thing would have happened to you. But not here, this is a tutorial.

				To continue, just drop out at the end of that gangway. The drop is safe.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_items" description="Items"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Throughout your journey, you will probably collect many items. Once you collected
				them, blocks are considered to be items, too.

				Items can be stored in your inventory and selected with the hotbar (see the other signs).
				You can wield any items; you can even punch with almost any item to hurt enemies.
				Usually, you will deal a minimal default damage with most items. Even if you do not hold,
				an item at all.
				If you don't want to have an item anymore, you can always throw it away. Likewise,
				you can collect items which lie around by pointing and leftclicking them.

					 Collect item: [Left mouse button]
					 Drop carried item stack: [Q]
					 Drop single item from carried item stack: [Shift] + [Q]

				On the table at the right to this sign lies an item stack of 50 rocks so you have some items,
				to test out the inventory.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_tools" description="Tools"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[A tool is a special kind of item.
				Tools can be used for many things, such as:
				- Breaking blocks
				- Collecting liquids
				- Rotating blocks
				- Many others!
				The number of tools which are possible in Minetest is innumberable and are
				too many to cover in this tutorial.
				But at least we will look at a very common and important tool type: mining tools,
				We will come to that in the mining section.

				Many tools wear off and get destroyed after you used them for a while. In an
				inventory the tool's "health" is indicated by a colored bar

				Tools may be able to be repaired, see the sign about repairing.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_inventory" description="Using the Inventory"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[The inventory menu usually contains the player inventory. This allows you
				to carry along items throughout the world.

				Every inventory is made out of slots where you can store items in. You can store one
				entire stack of items per slot, the only condition is that the items are of the same
				type. In this tutorial all items except for tools stack up to 99 items, but this number
				can vary in actual games.

				Here are the controls which explain how to move around the items within the inventory:

				In the game:
					 Open inventory menu: [I]

				When the inventory is opened and you don't hold any items:
					 Take item stack: [Left mouse button]
					 Take 10 items from item stack: [Middle mouse button]
					 Take half item stack: [Right mouse button]

				When you took an item stack in the inventory:
					 Put item stack: [Left mouse button]
					 Put 10 items from item stack: [Middle mouse button]
					 Put single item from item stack: [Right mouse button]

				You can also drop an item stack by holding it in the inventory, then clicking anywhere
				outside of the window.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_listrings" description="Inventory shortcut"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[By the way, if you are tired of clicking, there is a little convenience
				feature:
				Hold [Shift] while you left-click on an item stack in a menu to
				move it instantly to another relevant section. For example, in this tutorial
				you can use it to move an item stack from the chest into your inventory (and
				vice-versa) with a single click.

					 [Shift]+[Left click]: Move full item stack to other section in menu]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_chest" description="Comment About Chests"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[This is a chest. You can view its contents by right-clicking it. In the menu you will see
				two inventories, on the upper part the chest inventory and on the lower part the player
				inventory. Exchanging items works exactly the same as in the inventory menu.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_build" description="Building Some Blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Another important task in Minetest is building blocks.
				"Building" here refers to the task of placing one block in your possession onto
				another block in the world.
				Unlike mining, building a block happens instantanous. To build, select a block in your
				hotbar, point to any block in the world and press the right mouse button.
				Your block will be immediately placed on the pointed side.
				It is important that the block you want to build to is pointable. This means you cannot build
				next to or on liquids by normal means.

					 Build on ordinary block: [Right mouse button]

				Try to get up to that little hole by using the wood blocks in the chest. There is another
				gold ingot waiting for you.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_build_special" description="Building at Usable Blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[You may have wondered how you can build on a block which you can use, like a chest.
				For this, you have to hold the sneak key and then use the build key.

					 Build on usable block: [Shift] + [Right mouse button]]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_mine" description="Mining blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Mining is a method to remove a single block with a mining tool. It is a very important
				task in Minetest which you will use often.

				(It is recommended that you go to the crafting and items house first. It is right in front of
				this sign.)

				To be able to mine a block, you need

				1. to have minable block, after all,
				2. to point on the block and
				3. to carry an appropriate tool.

					 Mine: [Left mouse button]

				When you are ready, hold the left mouse button while pointing the block. Depending on
				the block type and the tool properties, this can take some time. Some tools are fast with
				some particular block types, some other tools may be slower to mine other block types.
				If you do not carry an appropriate tool, you are not able to mine the block at all.
				You can tell that you are actually mining when you see cracks or some other animation
				on the block in question.

				When done mining, blocks will often add one or more items to your inventory. This is called
				the "drop" of a block and depends on the block type. Now try to mine those large cubes in
				this area, using different tools. Note that all blocks here are just examples to show you
				different kinds of drops.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_mine_cobble" description="Mining example: Cobblestone"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[This is cobblestone. You can mine it with a pickaxe.
				This cobblestone will always drop itself, that means, cobblestone. Dropping itself is the
				usual dropping behaviour of a block, throughout many games.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_mine_stone" description="Mining example: Stone"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[This is stone. You need a pickaxe to mine it. When mined, stone will drop cobblestone.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_mine_conglomerate" description="Mining example: Conglomerate"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[This is a cube of conglomerate. You need a pickaxe to mine it.
				Conglomerate drops something based on probability. Conglomerate randomly drops between 1
				and 5 rocks, when mined.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_mine_wood" description="Mining example: Wooden Planks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[These are wooden planks. In the tutorial, you can only mine those blocks with an axe.
				Wooden planks drop themselves.

				In Minetest, we use the term "mining" in a general sense, regardless of the material.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_mine_glass" description="Mining example: Weak glass"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[This is some weak glass. You can break it with your bare hands. Or you can use your pickaxe,
				which is faster. Note that it looks slightly different than the other glass in this world.
				These glass blocks don't drop anything.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_mine_immortal" description="Unminable blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[There can always be some blocks which are not minable by any tool. In our tutorial, all
				those castle walls can't me mined, for example.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_blocks" description="Special blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[The world of Minetest is made entirely out of blocks, or voxels, to be precise.
				Blocks can be added or removed with the correct tools.

				In this section, we'll show you a few special but common blocks which behave in unexpected,
				ways.,

				Of course, games can come up with more special weird blocks.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_disable_jump" description="No-jumping blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[These nasty blocks on the floor prevent you from jumping when you stand on them.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_bouncy" description="Bouncy blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Whee! The blocks will make you bounce if you jump on them. They also can bounce
				you from the side, if you are fast enough.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_falling_node" description="Falling blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Some blocks need to rest on top of another block, otherwise, they fall down.
				Try it and mine the block below the uppermost block.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_attached_node" description="Attached blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Some blocks have to be attached to another block, otherwise, they drop as an item
				as if you would have mined it.

				Attached here is a picture frame. You can't collect or mine it directly, but if you mine
				the block it is attached to, it will drop as an item which you can collect.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_use" description="Using blocks"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[=[You will often meet some blocks you can use. Something special happens when you
				right-click while pointing on them.
				In fact, you already used such blocks: All the signs you read are "usable" blocks.

				There is a strange device next to this sign. Use it and see what happens.

					 Use usable block: [Right mouse button]]=]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_craft1" description="Crafting Basics"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Crafting is the task of taking several items and combining them to form a new item.
				Crafting is another important task in Minetest.

				To craft something, you need a few items and a so-called crafting grid.

				In this tutorial, you have a grid of size 3 times 3 in your inventory.
				Let's get right into crafting:

				1. Take 3 sheets of paper from the chest next to this sign.
				2. Open the inventory menu with [I].
				3. Place the paper in the crafting grid so that they form a 1×3 vertical line.
				4. A book should appear in the output slot. Click on it to take it,
					 then put it in your player inventory.

				This process consumes the paper.
				When you have the book in your inventory, go on with the next sign.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_craft2" description="Crafting using Shapeless Recipes"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[To craft the book you have used a so-called crafting recipe. You must know the crafting
				recipes as well so you can craft.

				The crafting recipe you used in particular is a so-called shaped recipe. This means the
				pattern you place in the crafting grid matters, but you can move the entire pattern
				freely.

				There is another kind of crafting recipe: Shapeless.
				Shapeless recipes only care about which items you place in the crafting grid, but not in
				which pattern. In the next chest you find some wheat. Let's make dough from it! For this,
				you have to place at least 1 wheat in 4 different slots, but the other slots must be empty.
				What is special about this recipe is that you can place them anywhere in the grid.

				When you got your dough, go on with the next sign.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_craft3" description="Crafting Faster"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Do you got your dough? Good.

				You may have noticed that crafting always consumes one item from each occupied slot
				of the crafting grid. This is true for all crafting recipes.
				You can speed crafting up a bit when you click with the middle mouse button on the
				item in the output slot. Doing so will attempt to do the same craft up to 10 times,
				instead of just once.

				Feel free to try it with the remaining wheat or just go on with the next sign.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_craft4" description="Crafting Groups"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Another important thing to know about crafting are so-called groups. Crafting recipes do
				not always require you to use the exactly same items every time.
				This tutorial has a special recipe for books. In the chest, you will find paper in 4
				different colors. You can also make a book by placing 3 paper sheets of any color
				in a vertical line.
				The paper color does not matter here, you can use only white paper, only orange paper
				or even mix it. What is important here are the occupied slots.
				This is possible because all 4 types of (example) paper belong to the same group and
				our book recipe accepts not only white paper, but any paper of that group.

				Feel free to experiment a bit around with this.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_smelt" description="Furnace Operation Instructions"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[This is a furnace. Furnaces can be used to turn a smeltable item with help of a fuel
				to a new item. Many items can be furnace fuels, but not all. A few items are smeltable.

				In order to operate a furnace, you have to put the smeltable item into the 'Source' slot
				and the fuel into the 'Fuel' slot.
				As soon as the items have been placed, the furnace automatically starts to smelt the
				items. The furnace becomes active and consumes an item in the fuel slot. The flame
				goes on and will continue burning for a given time. The time depends on the fuel type.
				Some fuels burn very short, and others burn longer. In the furnace menu, the burn time
				is indicated by the flame symbol. As soon as the flame goes out, the furnace may
				continue burning if there is still fuel and smeltable material in the furnace,
				otherwise, the furnace becomes inactive again.
				The smeltable material has to be exposed to the flame for a given time as well. This
				time depends on the type of the material, too. Some material smelt faster than others.
				You can see the smelting progress of a single item on the progress arrow. If one item
				has been smelt, the result goes to one of the output slots, where you can take it.

				In the left chest you find some fuels and in the right chest you find some materials to
				smelt. Feel free to experiment with the furnace a bit. Smelt the gold lump to receive
				this station's gold bar.

				Again, this furnace is just an example; the exact operation may differ slightly from
				game to game.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_repair" description="Repairing Tools"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Some games may come with a special recipe which allows you to repair your tools.
				In those, repairing works always the same way:
				Place two more or less worn out tools of the same kind into the crafting crid and
				take the result. The result is a new tool which is slightly repaired by a fixed percentage.

				Of course, this tutorial comes with such a recipe. The chest next to this sign stores
				some damaged tools which you may try to repair now.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_basic_end" description="End of the Basic Tutorial"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[If you think you have enough of this tutorial, you can leave at any time. There are
				13 gold ingots at the stations to be found, to help you keep track.

				You can find the gold ingots at the following stations:
				- Ladders
				- Sneaking
				- Swimming
				- Diving
				- Waterfall
				- Viscosity
				- Comestibles and Eating
				- Pointing
				- Crafting
				- Smelting
				- Mining
				- Building
				- Damage and Health

				If you've got 13 gold ingots (in total), you probably know now everything which can be
				learned from this tutorial. Collecting the gold ingots is optional.

				After you closed this dialog, you can press [Esc] to open the pause menu and return
				to the main menu or quit Minetest.

				In the next room there are some further signs with information, but it is entirely optional
				and not related to gameplay.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_controls" description="Controls Overview"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[To recap, here is an overview over the most important default controls:

					 Move forwards: [W]
					 Move left: [A]
					 Move backwards: [S]
					 Move right: [D]
					 Jump: [Space]
					 Sneak: [Shift]
					 Move upwards (ladder/liquid): [Space]
					 Move downwards (ladder/liquid): [Shift]

					 Toggle camera mode: [C]
					 Toggle minimap mode: [V]

					 Select item in hotbar: [Mouse wheel]
					 Select item in hotbar: [0] - [9]
					 Inventory menu: [I]

					 Collect pointed item: [Left mouse button]
					 Drop item stack: [Q]
					 Drop single item: [Shift] + [Q]

					 Punch: [Left mouse button]
					 Mine: [Left mouse button]
					 Build/use: [Right mouse button]
					 Build: [Shift] + [Right mouse button]

					 Abort/open pause menu: [Esc]

				You can review a shorter version of the controls in the pause menu.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_online" description="Online Resources"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[You may want to check out these online resources related to Minetest:

				Official homepage of Minetest: https://minetest.net/
				The main place to find the most recent version of Minetest.

				Community wiki: https://wiki.minetest.net/
				A community-based documentation website for Minetest. Anyone with an account can edit
				it! It also features a documentation of the default game, which was NOT covered by
				this tutorial.

				Webforums: https://forum.minetest.net/
				A web-based discussion platform where you can discuss everything related to Minetest.
				This is also a place where player-made mods and games are published and
				discussed. The discussions are mainly in English, but there is also space for
				discussion in other languages.

				Chat: irc://irc.freenode.net#minetest
				A generic Internet Relay Chat channel for everything related to Minetest where people can
				meet to discuss in real-time.
				If you do not understand IRC, see the Community Wiki for help.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>

	<Actor type="node" name="tutorial:sign_subgame" description="Games"
		resource="actors\minecraft\mods\tutorial\infos\infosign.xml">
		<ItemComponent>
			<Text>
				[[Now since you probably now the basics, you may want to actually play or build something.
				Minetest comes bundled with a default game, which you may try out now.
				Sadly, there is currently no tutorial for the default game.
				You may want to read the "Getting Started" section of the Community Wiki,
				which is more specific about the default game.
				Said document can be found at:

				https://wiki.minetest.net/Getting_Started

				Alternatively, you may check out one of the games which are shared on the Minetest forums.]]
			</Text>
		</ItemComponent>
	</Actor>
</Actors>